<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Title</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <div type="cover">
            <note> </note>
         </div>
         <div type="inlet">
            <head> </head>
         </div>
      </front>

      <body>
         <div type="spain">
            <ab> </ab>
         </div>
         <div type="portugal">
            <pb facs="#f-160" n="160"/>
            <fw>45</fw>
            <ab>At <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Seville the Alcazar</rs><note type="translation"
                  >Fortress</note> yet a Royal palace. Some is Moorish some of <rs type="person"
                  ref="XXX">Carlos V</rs>. the Lonja or exchange part of it <metamark>–</metamark>
               <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Palace of Dukes of Alcala</rs> fine moorish. <rs
                  type="person" ref="XXX">Medina Celi</rs> all the same. <rs type="place" ref="XXX"
                  >Triana the Suburb <choice>
                     <abbr>S</abbr>
                     <expan>South</expan>
                  </choice></rs>, of river. Walls almost entire. Many hermandades &amp;
                  confradias<note type="translation">fraternities and guilds</note> – Tricles with
               the river. Cortijos <note type="translation">Farmhouses</note> scattered, <rs
                  type="place" ref="XXX"><choice>
                     <abbr>Cazalla</abbr>
                     <ex>de la Sierra </ex>
                  </choice></rs>, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Constantina Aracena</rs> places for
               Summer retreat in <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Sierra Morena</rs>. </ab>
            <figure facs="f-vvvv">
               <note type="editorial_label"> Pen and ink drawing: shield </note>
               <label>Aben – Alhamar</label>
               <label>Sometimes red blue &amp; green shields</label>
            </figure>
            <ab>
               <note type="editorial"> Copied, translated or paraphrased from Conde, Historia de la
                  dominacion, vol. 3, pp. 38-9.</note>
               <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Alhamar King of Granada</rs>. Tomò por armas escudo
               campo de plata banda diagonal azul, y en ella escrito in letras de oro "le galib ile
               Ala" "no es vencedor sino Dios." porque sus pueblos le solian saludar con el titulo
               de Galib y el replicaba "Wa le galib ile Ala." y no hay mas vencedor que Ala." las
               estremos de la banda del escudo en bocas de dragones. His descendant bore same arms
               only varying the colors, to red blue &amp; green shields &amp; changed color of band
               also. He began the <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Alhambra</rs>, directed the work y
               andaba entre los alarifes y arquitectos muchas veces. The Court: <rs type="person"
                  ref="XXX">Abu Meruan Abdelmelic Juzef ben Senanid</rs> ilustre natural de Jaen
               primer Wazir. 2d. Wazir. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aly ben Ibrahim Asaibani
                  Azadi</rs>. de Granada, muy noble y rico. Capitan della Guardia <rs type="person"
                  ref="XXX">Muhamad hijo del Wazir Aly </rs> – he was also Alcayde. Wali o principal
               Caudillo de sus tropas <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Abdala Muhamad Arramim</rs>.
               Almirante o caudillo del mar el padre de este. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben
                  Muza</rs> Alcayde de su caballeria Secretario de su Mezuar o consejo <rs
                  type="person" ref="XXX">Yahye ben Alcatib de Granada</rs>. Alcatibes o secretarios
               para ordenes y cartas. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul Hasan Aly Arrayni</rs> 1 2
                  <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Becar ben Chatab</rs>. 3 <rs type="person"
                  ref="XXX">Abu Omar Juzef ben Said Alyahsi di Loxa</rs>. 7 Alcadies o jueces de
               corte. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Amer Yahye Alaschari</rs>. 2 <rs type="person"
                  ref="XXX">Abu Abdala Muhamad Alansari</rs> celebre jurisconsulto who wrote many
               works. 3 Cadi de lo criminal, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Abdala el Tamini de los
                  Asalamies de Loxa</rs>. 4 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Ayadh ben Muza el
                  Yahsabi</rs>. 5 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Adha</rs>. 6 <rs type="person"
                  ref="XXX">Abul Casem Abdala ben Abi Amer</rs>. 7 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben
                  Fat baron de Sevilla</rs>
               <metamark>–</metamark>
               <note type="translation"><rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Alhamar King of
                     Granada</rs>. He took for his arms a shield with a silver field and blue
                  diagonal band, on which was written in gold letters "le galib ile Ala" "there is
                  no victor but God." because his peoples <note type="editorial">or towns</note>
                  used to greet him with the title of Galib and he would reply "Wa le galib ile Ala"
                  and there is no other victor but Allah. The ends of the band on the shield in
                  dragons' mouths. His descendant bore same arms only varying the colors, to red
                     <note type="editorial">,</note> blue &amp; green shields &amp; changed color of
                  band also. He began the <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Alhambra</rs>, directed the
                  work and walked among the builders and architects many times. The Court: <rs
                     type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Meruan Abdelmelic Juzef ben Senanid</rs>
                  illustrious native of Jaen, first Wazir <note type="translation">minister</note>.
                  2nd Wazir. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aly ben Ibrahim Asaibani Azadi</rs> of
                  Granada, very noble and rich. Captain of the <note type="editorial">Conde has 'de
                     su': of his</note> Guard <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Muhamad son of Aly the
                     Wazir</rs> - he was also Governor. Wali or main Commander of his troops <rs
                     type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Abdala Muhamad Arramim</rs>. Admiral or sea
                  commander, the father of the latter. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Muza</rs>,
                  Leader <note type="editorial">or Governor</note> of his cavalry. Secretary of his
                  Mezuar or council, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Yahye ben Alcatib of Granada</rs>.
                  Alcatibes or secretaries for decrees and letters. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul
                     Hasan Aly Arrayni</rs> 1, 2 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Becar ben
                     Chatab</rs>, 3 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Omar Juzef ben Said Alyahsi of
                        <note type="editorial">Conde has 'de'</note> Loja</rs>. 7 qadis or court
                  judges. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Amer Yahye Alaschari</rs>. 2 <rs
                     type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Abdala Muhamad Alansari</rs>, famous jurisconsult
                  who wrote many works. 3 judge <note type="editorial">qadi</note> of criminal law,
                     <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Abdala el Tamini of the Asalamies of Loja</rs>.
                  4 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Ayadh ben Muza el Yahsabi</rs>. 5 <rs
                     type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Adha</rs>. 6 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul
                     Casem Abdala ben Abi Amer</rs>. 7 <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Fat baron of
                     Sevilla</rs>
                  <note type="editorial">erroneous translation of Conde's text: 'Aben Fat el
                     conocido por Alasbaron de Sevilla': <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Fat, known
                        as Alasbaron of Seville</rs></note></note>
            </ab>
         </div>
         <div type="reading_notes">
            <ab> </ab>
         </div>
      </body>

      <back>
         <div type="cover">
            <note> </note>
         </div>
         <div type="index"> </div>
      </back>
   </text>

</TEI>
