<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Title</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <div type="cover">
            <note> </note>
         </div>
         <div type="inlet">
            <head> </head>
         </div>
      </front>

      <body>
         <div type="spain">
            <ab> </ab>
         </div>
         <div type="portugal">
            <ab> </ab>
         </div>
         <div type="reading_notes">
            <pb facs="#f-169" n="169"/>
            <fw>36</fw>
            <label><rs type="person" ref="XXX">Conde</rs> Followed</label>
            <note type="editorial">Extracts from/summary of <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Conde</rs>, Historia de la dominacion, vol.
               1, pp. xxi-xxiv.</note>
            <!-- refers to the whole document -->
            <ab> Works of <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Abdala Muhamad ben Abi Nasr el Homaidi</rs> de <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Cordova</rs>. Cronica de la
               conquista de <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Espa&#xF1;a</rs>. Amires &amp;c la serie de los Beni Omeyas, Reyes de Cordoba, y
               vidas de varones ilustres de <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Espa&#xF1;a</rs>. <date when="0450" calendar="islamic">450 de
                  Hegira</date> continued by Ahmed ben Yahye ben Ahmed ben Omeira Edobi de Mallorca
               <date when="0560" calendar="islamic">560</date>. El Homaidi cita<rs type="person" ref="XXX"> Abdelmelic ben
                  Habib Zalemi</rs>,<rs type="person" ref="XXX"> Abdala ben Junes</rs>,<rs type="person" ref="XXX"> Abdala ben Wahib</rs>, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Alaitz ben Saad</rs> y <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul Casem
               Abderahman ben Abdala ben Abdelhakem</rs> all writers of the oldest times. Es un tomo en
               folio escrito en papel moreno y grueso Asimismo <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Alabar, el Codai Valenciano</rs>
               escritor muy docto y extractò mucho de <rs>Abu Meruan ben Hayan ben Chalif</rs>. Tambien de
               los anales de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul Hassan ben Besam</rs> de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Mocri abu Abdala ben Abdelaziz ben Saad Axati</rs>,
               y de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Iza ben Ahmed ben Muhamad ben Muza el Razif</rs>, y de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Muhamad Abu Becar ben Jucef
               ben Casem Xelbi</rs> en su historia de <rs>Aben Abed Rey de Sevilla</rs>. Obra de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Meraudi</rs>
               intitulada “Prados Aureos”. <date when="0327" calendar="islamic">327</date> de los
               Arabes y la expedicion de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abderraman III</rs>, talas y conquistas reciprocas de <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Zamora</rs> por
               las tropas del <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Rey de Cordoba</rs> y los Xtianos acaudillados por el <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Rey Radmir de
               Galicia</rs>. <date when="0327" calendar="islamic">327</date> hasta <date when="0336"
                  calendar="islamic">336</date>. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul Casem Chalaf ben Abdelmelic ben Bascual de
               Cordoba</rs> hasta el quinto siglo de la Hegira un tomo in folio. 
               
               <note type="translation"
                  > Works of <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Abadala Muhamad ben Abi Nasr el Homaidi <note type="editorial">i.e.
                     Al-Humaydi</note> of Cordoba</rs>. Chronicle of the conquest of <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Spain</rs>. Emirs etc.
                  the succession of the Beni Omeyas <note type="editorial">Umayyads</note>, Kings of
                  Cordoba, and lives of illustrious men of Spain. <date when="0450"
                     calendar="islamic">AH 450 <note type="editorial">Anno Hegirae: Islamic
                        calendar</note></date>
                  <!-- is this how we should encode a date of Islamic calendar? --> continued by
                  Ahmed ben Yahye ben Ahmed ben Omeira, Edobi of Mallorca, <date when="0560"
                     calendar="islamic">560</date>. Al-Humaydi cites <note type="editorial">Conde
                        has 'cita a...'</note> <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdelmelic ben Habib Zalemi</rs>, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdala ben Junes</rs>, <rs type="person" ref="XXX" >Abdala
                           ben Wahib</rs>, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Alaitz ben Saad</rs> and <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul Casem Abderahman ben Abdala ben Abdelhaken</rs> all
                  writers of the oldest times. It is a volume in folio written on brown and coarse
                  paper. In addition <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Alabar, el Codai, of Valencia</rs>, very learned writer and he
                  extracts much from <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Meruan ben Hayan ben Chalf</rs> <note type="editorial">according
                     to Conde</note>. Also from the annals of <rs>Abul Hasan</rs> <note type="editorial"
                        >Conde</note>, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">ben Besam</rs>, <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Mocri abu Abdala ben Abdelaziz ben Saad Axati</rs>, and
                  <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Iza ben Ahmed ben Muhamad ben Muza el Razif</rs>, and <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Muhamad Abu Becar ben Jucef ben
                     Casem Xelbi</rs> in his history of <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Aben Abed, King of Seville</rs>. Work of <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Meraudi</rs> entitled
                  'Golden Meadows'. <date when="0327" calendar="islamic">327 of the Arabs <note
                     type="editorial">i.e. AH 327</note></date> and the expedition of <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abderraman
                        III</rs>, cutting down and reciprocal conquests of <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Zamora</rs> by the troops of the <rs type="person" ref="XXX">King of
                           Cordoba</rs> and the Christians led by <rs type="person" ref="XXX">King Radmir of Galicia</rs>. <date when="0327"
                     calendar="islamic">[AH] 327</date> to <date when="0336" calendar="islamic">[AH]
                        336</date>. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abul Casem Chalaf ben Abdelmelic ben Bascual of Cordoba</rs> <note
                     type="editorial">covers the period</note> until the <date notBefore="0401" notAfter="0500" calendar="islamic">fifth century of Hegira</date>, a
                  volume in folio.</note></ab>

            <metamark/>
            <cb/>

            <ab>Epoch of the Almoravides y de los Almohades en la historia de Fez de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdel Halim de
               Granada</rs> <date when="0726">726</date> – tomo en quarto en papel. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Lizan-Edin ben Alchatib Asalemani</rs> Secretario
               de los Reyes de Granada. called El Plenilunio de la dymnastia Nasrina en Granada: y 3
               tomos en folio biograficas 2 Memorias 1. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdala Algiazami de Malaga</rs> wrote Granada y
               la historia de sus Reyes. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Ahmed Almaxarsi</rs> del <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Rey Jucef Abul Hagiag el augusto de
               Granada</rs>. Y de la de los Beni Merinas in prose &amp; verse by <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Ismail ben Jucef Amir de
               Malaga</rs>, intitulada “Olor de la rosa”. Anales de Abulfeda, los de Xakiki y de Fesani
               Anales de Aben Sohna. Obra de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abu Teib de Ronda</rs> anecdotes of Princes &amp; Arabs
               &amp;c Obra rara de <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdala Aly ben Abderahman ben Huzeil de Granada</rs>. expediciones
               sacras o guerras contra Christianos, de arte militar de hacer frontera, de ardides y
               estrategemas de guerra, armas, maquinas, y caballeria. es muy curioso en los usos y
               costumbres de los Arabes Espa&#xF1;oles. Tomo in folio escrito en papel moreno y grueso,
               de harta antigüedad. La mayor parte de estos M.S.S estan en <rs type="place" ref="XXX">la Bibliotheca Real
               publica en Madrid</rs> y en <rs type="place" ref="XXX">la Escorial</rs> At <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Paris in Royal library</rs> “Historia de Espana y su
               description por <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Ahmed el Mocri Almagrebi</rs> in Arabic. <rs type="peron" ref="XXX">Condes</rs> book. La primera trata de
               la entrada de los Arabes en Espana, y la sucesion de los Amires, o caudillos de la
               conquista dependientes de los Calyfas de Oriente. La 2a contiene el establecimiento
               de la monarquia de los Beni Omeyas y la sucesion de estos Reyes. La tercera comprende
               la guerra civil y division de los reynos en <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Espa&#xF1;a</rs>: venida de los Almoravides y
               Almohades y la sucesion de estas dymnastias. Y la quarta es toda del <rs type="place" ref="XXX">reyno de Granada</rs>
               ultimo period de la dominacion Arabiga en <rs type="place" ref="XXX">Espa&#xF1;a</rs>. <note type="translation">Epoch of
                  the Almoravids and Almohads in the history of Fez by <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdel Halim of Granada</rs> <date when="0726">726</date> -
                  volume in quarto on paper. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Lizan-Edin ben Alchatib Asalemani</rs>, Secretary to the
                  Kings of Granada. Called the Full Moon of the Nasrid dynasty in Granada: and 3
                  volumes in folio, 2 biographical and 1 memoirs. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdala Algiazami of Málaga</rs> wrote
                  Granada and the history of its Kings. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Ahmed Almaxarsi</rs> <note type="editorial">wrote</note> about <rs type="person" ref="XXX">King Jucef
                  Abul Hagiag the august of Granada</rs>. And of the <note type="editorial">history</note> of the Beni Merinas in
                  prose and verse by <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Ismail ben Jucef, Emir of Málaga</rs>, entitled 'Scent of the rose'.
                  Annals of Abulfeda, those of Xakiki and of Fesani Annals of Aben Sohna. Work of
                  <rs type="person">Abu Teib of Ronda</rs> anecdotes of Princes and Arabs etc Rare work of <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Abdala Aly ben
                  Abderahman ben Huzeil of Granada</rs>. <note type="editorial">Treats of</note> holy expeditions or wars against
                  Christians <note type="editorial"><rs type="person" ref="XXX">Conde</rs>: 'Cristianos'</note>, of the art of war, of making frontiers, of
                  schemes and strategies of war, weapons, siege engines, and cavalry. It is very
                  curious on the usages and customs of the Spanish Arabs. Volume in folio written on
                  brown, coarse paper, of great antiquity. Most of these manuscripts are in the
                  <rs type="place" ref="XXX">royal public library <note type="editorail"><rs type="person" ref="XXX">Conde</rs>: 'biblioteca'</note> of Madrid and the Escorial</rs>. At Paris in
                  Royal library 'History of Spain and its description<note type="editorial">'</note> by <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Ahmed el Mocri Almagrebi</rs>
                  in Arabic. <rs type="person" ref="XXX">Conde</rs>'s book. The first <note type="editorial">volume</note> deals with the arrival of the Arabs in
                  Spain, and the succession of the Emirs, or leaders of conquest, dependent on the
                  Caliphs of the East. The second contains the establishment of the monarchy of the
                  Beni Omeyas <note type="editorial">Umayyads</note> and the succession of these Kings. The third comprises the
                  civil war and division of the kingdoms of Spain: the coming of the Almoravids and
                  the Almohads and the succession of these dynasties. And the whole of the fourth is
                  about the <rs type="place" ref="XXX">kingdom of Granada</rs>, the last period of Arab domination in
               Spain.</note></ab>
         </div>
      </body>

      <back>
         <div type="cover">
            <note> </note>
         </div>
         <div type="index"> </div>
      </back>
   </text>

</TEI>
